Association on American Indian Affairs Records, 1851-2016 (bulk 1922-1995): Finding Aid MC147
Public Policy Papers
- Series 2: Subject Files, 1851-1995; 332 boxes
  - Subseries 2: Tribal, 1852-1994; 120 boxes
    - Oklahoma, 1881-1991; 4 boxes
      - Osage, 1881-1906; 1934-1935; 1953-1955; 1971-1980; 1985-1987; 7 folders (Box 279, Folder 6-12)
      - Osage, undated; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 1)
      - "The Osage People And Their Trust Property", 1953; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 2)
      - Otoe-Missouria, 1956; 1974-1991; 2 folders (Box 280, Folder 3-4)
      - Pawnee, 1949-1959; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 5)
      - Quapaw, 1953-1959; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 6)
      - Seminole, 1957-1960; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 7)
      - Statue of Sequoyah, Capitol, Washington, D.C., 1963; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 8)
      - Tax Sales, 1959; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 9)
      - Welfare Assistance, 1957; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 10)
      - Wichita, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 11)
      - Wyandotte, 1955-1959; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 12)
      - General, 1934-1938; 1953-1974; 1982-1990; 3 folders (Box 280, Folder 13-15)
    - Oregon, 1929-1994; 3 boxes
      - Burns Paiute, 1988; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 16)
      - Celilo Falls, 1952-1960; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 17)
      - Child Welfare, 1977-1989; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 18)
      - Crow's Shadow Institute, 1994; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 19)
      - Gold Beach Land Swindle, 1952-1960; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 1)
      - Grand Ronde, 1987; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 2)
      - Grand Ronde Constitution, 1936; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 3)
      - Klamath, 1929-1972; 1979-1993; 4 folders (Box 281, Folder 4-7)
      - Oregon Council of Churches, 1958-1959; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 8)
      - Organization of the Forgotten American, 1970-1979; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 9)
      - Warm Springs, 1958-1974; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 10)
      - General, 1951-1958; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 11)
      - General, 1983-1993; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania, 1950-1953; 1 box
      - Cornplanter Seneca, 1950-1953; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 2)
    - Rhode Island, 1935-1959; 1 box
      - Narragansett, 1935-1959; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 3)
    - South Carolina, 1945-1993; 1 box
      - Catawba, 1949-1962; 1993; 3 folders (Box 282, Folder 4-6)
      - Grave of Osceola, 1968; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 7)
      - "The Mestizos of South Carolina", 1945; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 8)
    - Tennessee, 1975-1987; 1 box
      - Etowah Cherokee, 1975-1987; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 9)
    - Texas, 1953-1987; 1 box
      - Alabama-Coushatta, 1953-1962; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 10)
      - Federal Recognition of Tribes, 1985-1987; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 11)
    - Utah, 1951-1988; 2 boxes
      - Child Welfare, 1969-1977; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 12)
      - Paiute, 1982-1984; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 13)
      - True Utes, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 14)
      - Ute, 1951-1961; 1975-1988; 2 folders (Box 283, Folder 1-2)
    - Vermont, 1952-1990; 1 box
      - Abenaki, 1990; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 3)
      - Iroquois Claims, 1952-1953; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 4)
    - Virginia, 1942-1959; 1 box
      - Chickahominy, 1942-1959; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 5)
      - Rappahannock, 1943; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 6)
    - Washington, 1854-1993; 6 boxes
      - Chief Joseph Dam, 1956; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 7)
      - Child Welfare (Including Tribal-State Agreement), 1973-1983; 3 folders (Box 283, Folder 8-10)
      - Child Welfare (Including Tribal-State Agreement), 1983-1988; undated; 5 folders (Box 284, Folder 1-5)
      - Chinook, 1953-1959; 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 284, Folder 6-7)
      - Colville, 1938-1970; 1978-1984; 2 folders (Box 284, Folder 8-9)
      - Colville Lands, 1949-1962; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 1)
      - Cowlitz, 1975; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 2)
      - Hoh, 1973-1974; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 3)
      - Indian Youth Development Committee, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 4)
      - Kalispel, 1973; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 5)
      - Law and Order, 1959-1963; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 6)
      - Lummi, 1951-1976; 1986; 2 folders (Box 285, Folder 7-8)
      - Makah, 1954-1963; 1975; 2 folders (Box 285, Folder 9-10)
      - Muckleshoot, 1969-1971; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 11)
      - Nisqually, 1957-1976; 2 folders (Box 285, Folder 12-13)
      - Nooksack, 1961; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 14)
      - Northwest Indian Fisheries Commission, 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 15)
      - Northwest Intertribal Court System, 1982; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 16)
      - Puyallup, undated; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 17)
      - Quileute-Hoh-Queets-Quinault Treaty Fish Commission, 1970; 1 folder (Box 285, Folder 18)
      - Quinault, 1952-1962; 1975-1989; 2 folders (Box 286, Folder 1-2)
      - Salish, 1957; 1 folder (Box 286, Folder 3)
      - Samish, 1989-1993; 1 folder (Box 286, Folder 4)
      - Skokomish, 1960-1962; 1986; 2 folders (Box 286, Folder 5-6)
      - Small Tribes Organization of Western Washington, 1968-1974; 2 folders (Box 286, Folder 7-8)
      - Snohomish, 1989; 1 folder (Box 286, Folder 9)
      - Squaxin Island, 1854; 1959-1973; 2 folders (Box 286, Folder 10-11)
      - Swinomish, 1956-1960; 1 folder (Box 286, Folder 12)
      - Tulalip, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Box 286, Folder 13)
      - Tulalip, 1989; 1 folder (Box 287, Folder 1)
      - "Washington's 'Landless' Tribes", undated; 1 folder (Box 287, Folder 2)
      - Western Washington Health Conference, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 287, Folder 3)
      - Yakima, 1953-1974; 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 287, Folder 4-5)
      - General, 1951-1962; 3 folders (Box 287, Folder 6-8)
      - General, 1970-1975; 1982-1985; undated; 4 folders (Box 288, Folder 1-4)
    - Wisconsin, 1854-1990; 4 boxes
      - Anti-Indian Sentiment, 1987-1989; 1 folder (Box 288, Folder 5)
      - Apostle Islands, 1970; 1 folder (Box 288, Folder 6)
      - Bad River Chippewa, 1959; 1 folder (Box 288, Folder 7)
      - Bad River Chippewa and Madeline Island, 1854-1936; 1967-1975; 1979-1987; 3 folders (Box 288, Folder 8-10)
      - Child Welfare, 1972-1976; 1979-1984; undated; 3 folders (Box 288, Folder 11-13)
      - Chippewa, 1959-1967; 1989; 2 folders (Box 288, Folder 14-15)
      - First American Human Services, 1982-1986; 1 folder (Box 289, Folder 1)
      - Forest County Potawatomi, 1932-1937; 1 folder (Box 289, Folder 2)
      - Great Lakes Inter-Tribal Council, 1966-1972; 1 folder (Box 289, Folder 3)
      - Indian Community School of Milwaukee, 1971-1973; 1986; 2 folders (Box 289, Folder 4-5)
      - Lac Courte Oreilles Chippewa, 1969-1970; 1 folder (Box 289, Folder 6)
      - Lac du Flambeau Chippewa, 1951-1959; 1 folder (Box 289, Folder 7)
      - Menominee, 1950-1975; 1990; 4 folders (Box 289, Folder 8-11)
      - Menominee, undated; 1 folder (Box 290, Folder 1)
      - Oneida, 1937-1958; 1965-1976; 4 folders (Box 290, Folder 2-5)
      - Oneida and Green Bay and Western Railway Right-of-Way, 1867-1937; 1971-1974; 2 folders (Box 290, Folder 6-7)
      - Stockbridge-Munsee Mohican, 1937-1974; 1 folder (Box 290, Folder 8)
      - Stockbridge-Munsee Mohican, 1982-1983; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 1)
      - Wisconsin Winnebago, 1960-1976; 1982-1985; 2 folders (Box 291, Folder 2-3)
      - Wisconsin Winnebago Potch-Chee-Nunk Child Welfare Project, 1976-1978; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 4)
      - General, 1937-1973; 1984; 2 folders (Box 291, Folder 5-6)
    - Wyoming, 1938-1993; 1 box
      - Wind River Arapahoe and Shoshone Economic Development, 1982-1990; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 7)
      - Wind River Arapahoe and Shoshone: Oil Leases, 1981; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 8)
      - Wind River Arapahoe and Shoshone Water Rights, 1973-1976; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 9)
      - "Wind River Indian Needs Determination Survey", undated; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 10)
      - Wyoming Indian High School, 1993; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 11)
      - Wyoming Indian Leadership Council, 1972; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 12)
      - General, 1938-1992; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: Legislation, 1851-1994; 38 boxes
    All records in Series 2, Subseries 3 are open for research use.
    Series 2: Subject Files, Subseries 3: Legislation (1851-1994) consists of correspondence, articles, memoranda, and Congressional bills, resolutions, reports, and testimony relating to a wide variety of legislative and administrative issues of concern to the AAIA. These are embodied in sometimes voluminous subject files and an extensive series of memoranda containing synopses of governmental activities impinging on Native Americans. The bulk of the latter were prepared for general circulation by the AAIA's general counsel. The scope of this subseries reflects the importance the AAIA attached to effecting change in Washington, be it in a supportive or an adversarial role. Leaders of the Association such as President Oliver La Farge, General Counsel Richard Schifter, and Executive Director William Byler took an interest in everything from the implications of Alaskan statehood to the protection and repatriation of Indian remains and artifacts to the transfer of civil and criminal jurisdiction from federal to state authorities. Attention was given to measures affecting every tribe, such as the far-reaching Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act of 1975, which sought to give Native Americans a meaningful say in programs intended for their benefit, as well as to localized initiatives, such as the resolution politicizing the superintendency of the Five Civilized Tribes in Oklahoma in 1935.
    Some matters, of course, received more attention than others. Files such as "Pueblo Lands," which documents the formative struggle of the AAIA, then known as the Eastern Association on Indian Affairs, to safeguard the dwindling land base of New Mexico's Pueblo Indians in the 1920s, and "Indian Child Welfare Act," a major focus of concern in the 1970s and 1980s, are remarkable for their depth. Such files illustrate the significant role played by the AAIA in influencing Congressional action not only through detailed critiques but through the submission of draft legislation. Although other files, such as those addressing issues of economic development, juvenile alcohol and drug abuse, law enforcement, and sanitation, are not as large, they, too, shed light on the sometimes subtle, sometimes explicit pressures exerted by the AAIA when policymakers considered laws and regulations affecting Native Americans.
    Not only does this subseries chronicle many decades of public debate over the proper scope and direction of federal Indian policy, but it offers insights into the internal discussions which determined the nature and tone of the AAIA's position in this volatile arena. In either case, the stakes were large, for if these files make one thing plain, it is that the federal government has exercised enormous influence for good and ill in the lives of Native Americans. Indeed, their very survival as tribal entities has, at times, hung in the balance. Even when legislation favorable to them has been enacted, as in the case of the groundbreaking Indian Reorganization Act of 1934, there has been no guarantee that it would not be repealed or emasculated in a subsequent session of Congress. From the struggle over Indian religious freedom to the struggle over the termination of federal responsibilities, it is clear from this subseries that the AAIA has played a significant role in safeguarding fundamental Native American interests through legislative and administrative action.
    The materials in this subseries are arranged in two general groupings: files containing legislative and administrative memoranda in chronological order are followed by files arranged alphabetically by subject or type of legislation (e.g., "Child Welfare" or "Appropriations"
    - Legislative and Administrative Memoranda, 1926-1935; 1 folder (Box 291, Folder 14)
    - Legislative and Administrative Memoranda, 1940-1954; 1957-1968; 1972-1974; 5 folders (Box 292, Folder 1-5)
    - Legislative and Administrative Memoranda, 1976-1982; 6 folders (Box 293, Folder 1-6)
    - Legislative and Administrative Memoranda, 1983-1991; undated; 7 folders (Box 294, Folder 1-7)
    - Legislative Program of AAIA, 1948-1956; 1 folder (Box 294, Folder 8)
    - Adoption, 1975-1981; 1 folder (Box 294, Folder 9)
    - Alaska Fishery, 1941-1944; 1 folder (Box 294, Folder 10)
    - Alaska Native Claims, 1948-1959; 1967-1970; 6 folders (Box 295, Folder 1-6)
    - Alaska Native Claims, 1971; 1984-1986; 4 folders (Box 296, Folder 1-4)
    - Alaska Native Claims, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 297, Folder 1-2)
    - Alaska Reservations Revocation, 1947-1949; 1 folder (Box 297, Folder 3)
    - Alaska Salmon Trap Sites, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 297, Folder 4)
    - Alaska Statehood, 1948-1950; 2 folders (Box 297, Folder 5-6)
    - Alaska Statehood, 1951-1955; 1 folder (Box 298, Folder 1)
    - Alaska Townsites, 1954-1962; 1 folder (Box 298, Folder 2)
    - Alaska Tribal Government, 1977; 1 folder (Box 298, Folder 3)
    - Alcohol and Drug Abuse, 1987; 1 folder (Box 298, Folder 4)
    - Appropriations, 1932-1955; 1957-1965; 4 folders (Box 298, Folder 5-8)
    - Appropriations, 1966-1978; 1980-1983; 5 folders (Box 299, Folder 1-5)
    - Appropriations, 1983-1990; 5 folders (Box 300, Folder 1-5)
    - Appropriations, 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 1)
    - Arctic Research and Policy Act, 1981-1982; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 2)
    - Arts and Crafts, 1930-1935; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 3)
    - Blackfeet Affairs, 1952; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 4)
    - Blackfeet Rehabilitation, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 5)
    - Board of Public Lands Appeals, 1962; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 6)
    - Boysen Dam, 1952; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 7)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs Appointments, 1933; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 8)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs Funding, 1933; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 9)
    - Child Abuse, 1973-1991; 2 folders (Box 301, Folder 10-11)
    - Child Care, 1974-1991; 1 folder (Box 301, Folder 12)
    - Child Welfare, 1973-1975; 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 301, Folder 13-14)
    - Child Welfare, 1990-1991; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 1)
    - Chippewa-Cree Rehabilitation, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 2)
    - Citizenship, 1924; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 3)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps, 1950; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 4)
    - Clean Air Act, 1981; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 5)
    - Cleveland National Forest, 1962; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 6)
    - Constitutional Rights, 1961-1975; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 7)
    - Custer Battlefield National Indian Memorial, 1991; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 8)
    - Death Penalty, 1989-1991; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 9)
    - Definition of Indian, 1954; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 10)
    - Department of Defense Buy Indian Act, 1982-1987; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 11)
    - The Disabled, 1985-1988; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 12)
    - Eagles, 1962; 1 folder (Box 302, Folder 13)
    - Economic Development, 1956-1965; 1985-1993; 2 folders (Box 302, Folder 14-15)
    - Education, 1949-1972; 1978-1990; 2 folders (Box 303, Folder 1-2)
    - Electric Power, 1967; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 3)
    - Espionage, 1932-1934; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 4)
    - Fair Employment Practices, 1949; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 5)
    - Family Welfare, 1970-1988; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 6)
    - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome, 1990; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 7)
    - Fishing Vessels, 1956; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 8)
    - Five Civilized Tribes' Lands, 1932-1933; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 9)
    - Five Civilized Tribes' Superintendency, 1935; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 10)
    - Food Programs, 1959-1977; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 11)
    - Fort Randall Dam, 1952-1954; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 12)
    - Four States Bills, 1957-1958; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 13)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 1975; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 14)
    - Gaming, 1983-1985; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 15)
    - Gros Ventre and Assiniboine Lands, 1954; 1 folder (Box 303, Folder 16)
    - Gros Ventre and Assiniboine Rehabilitation, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 304, Folder 1)
    - Health, 1968-1989; 4 folders (Box 304, Folder 2-5)
    - Hospitals, 1949-1957; 1 folder (Box 304, Folder 6)
    - Housing, 1949-1968; 1980-1989; 2 folders (Box 304, Folder 7-8)
    - Indian Child Welfare Act, 1975-1979; 5 folders (Box 305, Folder 1-5)
    - Indian Child Welfare Act, 1979-1987; 5 folders (Box 306, Folder 1-5)
    - Indian Child Welfare Act, 1987-1991; 5 folders (Box 307, Folder 1-5)
    - Indian Child Welfare Act, undated; 2 folders (Box 308, Folder 1-2)
    - Indian Claims, 1939-1941; 1 folder (Box 308, Folder 3)
    - Indian Claims Commission Act, 1945-1947; 1 folder (Box 308, Folder 4)
    - Indian Claims Commission Act Extension, 1951-1972; 2 folders (Box 308, Folder 5-6)
    - Indian Claims Commission Act Reversal, 1947-1961; 1 folder (Box 308, Folder 7)
    - Indian Competency, 1947-1951; 1 folder (Box 308, Folder 8)
    - Indian Competency, 1953-1954; 2 folders (Box 309, Folder 1-2)
    - Indian Development Finance Corporation Act, 1987-1989; 1 folder (Box 309, Folder 3)
    - Indian Financing Act, 1983-1990; 1 folder (Box 309, Folder 4)
    - Indian Lands, 1943-1973; 1 folder (Box 309, Folder 5)
    - Indian Lands, 1980-1983; 1 folder (Box 310, Folder 1)
    - Indian Rehabilitation, 1941-1956; 1 folder (Box 310, Folder 2)
    - Indian Reorganization Act, 1933-1947; undated; 3 folders (Box 310, Folder 3-5)
    - Indian Reorganization Act Reversal, 1937; 1939-1940; 2 folders (Box 310, Folder 6-7)
    - Indian Reorganization Act Reversal, 1940-1944; 1 folder (Box 311, Folder 1)
    - Indian Tribal Governmental Tax Status Act, 1981-1985; undated; 3 folders (Box 311, Folder 2-4)
    - Indian Trust Counsel Authority, 1971-1975; 1 folder (Box 311, Folder 5)
    - Indian Trust Estates, 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 311, Folder 6)
    - Job Creation, 1983; 1 folder (Box 311, Folder 7)
    - Judicial System, 1962-1986; 1 folder (Box 311, Folder 8)
    - Juvenile Alcohol and Drug Abuse, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 311, Folder 9)
    - Juvenile Alcohol and Drug Abuse, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 312, Folder 1-2)
    - Juvenile Delinquency, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 3)
    - Law Enforcement, 1952-1970; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 4)
    - Leasing of Indian Lands, 1937-1961; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 5)
    - Liquor Bans and Other Discriminatory Laws, 1949-1958; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 6)
    - Loans To Indians, 1949-1970; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 7)
    - "The Longest Walk", 1978; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 8)
    - Marine Mammals, 1961-1963; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 9)
    - Migratory Labor, 1952-1961; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 10)
    - Minnesota Chippewa Lands, 1962-1963; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 11)
    - Minnesota Indian Rehabilitation, 1955; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 12)
    - Mission Indian Lands, 1937-1954; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 13)
    - National Archives, 1983; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 14)
    - National Health Insurance and Public Health Act, 1949; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 15)
    - National Indian Research Institute, 1993; 1 folder (Box 312, Folder 16)
    - National Museum of the American Indian, 1986-1990; undated; 4 folders (Box 313, Folder 1-4)
    - Natural Gas for Barrow, Alaska, 1961-1963; 1 folder (Box 313, Folder 5)
    - Natural Resources, 1967-1979; 1 folder (Box 313, Folder 6)
    - Navajo-Hopi Rehabilitation, 1947-1949; 2 folders (Box 313, Folder 7-8)
    - Navajo-Hopi Rehabilitation, 1949-1955; undated; 3 folders (Box 314, Folder 1-3)
    - New Federalism for American Indians, 1989-1990; 1 folder (Box 314, Folder 4)
    - Oahe Dam, 1949-1954; 1 folder (Box 314, Folder 5)
    - Oglala Sioux Lands, 1951-1953; 1 folder (Box 314, Folder 6)
    - Oklahoma Indian Rehabilitation, 1934-1953; 1 folder (Box 314, Folder 7)
    - Older Americans Indian Services Improvement Act, 1987; 1 folder (Box 314, Folder 8)
    - Omnibus Legislation, 1923; 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 314, Folder 9-10)
    - Operation Bootstrap, 1958-1967; 1 folder (Box 314, Folder 11)
    - Parental Kidnapping, 1986; 1 folder (Box 315, Folder 1)
    - Point IV Program For American Indians, 1956-1961; 1 folder (Box 315, Folder 2)
    - Predator Control, 1962; 1 folder (Box 315, Folder 3)
    - Protection and Repatriation of Indian Remains and Artifacts, 1979-1990; 4 folders (Box 315, Folder 4-7)
    - Protection and Repatriation of Indian Remains and Artifacts, 1990-1993; undated; 5 folders (Box 316, Folder 1-5)
    - Pueblo Lands (Including Walker, Roberts Correspondence), 1851-1907; 1922-1923; 6 folders (Box 317, Folder 1-6)
    - Pueblo Lands (Including Walker, Roberts Correspondence), 1923-1924; 5 folders (Box 318, Folder 1-5)
    - Pueblo Lands (Including Walker, Roberts Correspondence), 1926-1934; undated; 2 folders (Box 319, Folder 1-2)
    - Pueblo of Santo Domingo Lands, 1958-1959; 1 folder (Box 319, Folder 3)
    - Radiation Exposure Compensation, 1978-1988; 3 folders (Box 319, Folder 4-6)
    - Reclamation Lands Family Farm Act, 1977-1978; 1 folder (Box 319, Folder 7)
    - Religious Freedom, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 319, Folder 8)
    - Religious Freedom, 1988-1993; 5 folders (Box 320, Folder 1-5)
    - Religious Freedom, 1993-1994; undated; 2 folders (Box 321, Folder 1-2)
    - Repeal of Congressional Power to Regulate Commerce with Tribes, 1951-1954; 1 folder (Box 321, Folder 3)
    - Revolving Loan Fund, 1959-1966; 1 folder (Box 321, Folder 4)
    - Rio Grande Flood Control, 1941-1943; 2 folders (Box 321, Folder 5-6)
    - Salish and Kootenai Lands, 1967; 1 folder (Box 321, Folder 7)
    - Sanitation, 1956-1961; 1 folder (Box 321, Folder 8)
    - Science and Technology, 1965; 1 folder (Box 321, Folder 9)
    - Self-Determination, 1973-1974; 1 folder (Box 321, Folder 10)
    - Self-Determination, 1975-1990; 2 folders (Box 322, Folder 1-2)
    - Sexual Offenses, 1984-1986; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 3)
    - Sisseton-Wahpeton Sioux Rehabilitation, 1949-1953; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 4)
    - Social Security, 1953; 1978; 2 folders (Box 322, Folder 5-6)
    - Social Services Funding, 1979-1992; 2 folders (Box 322, Folder 7-8)
    - Standing Rock Sioux Rehabilitation, 1949-1951; 1 folder (Box 322, Folder 9)
    - Statute Revision and Codification, 1931-1932; 1977-1986; 2 folders (Box 323, Folder 1-2)
    - Submarginal Lands, 1949-1960; 1 folder (Box 323, Folder 3)
    - Subsurface Rights, 1953; 1 folder (Box 323, Folder 4)
    - Sunset Legislation, 1978-1980; 1 folder (Box 323, Folder 5)
    - Tax Exemption Denial to Organizations Promoting Litigation, 1956; 1 folder (Box 323, Folder 6)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to California Indians (Including Elkus, Charles de Y. Correspondence), 1947-1953; 3 folders (Box 323, Folder 7-9)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to California Indians (Including Elkus, Charles de Y. Correspondence), 1953-1961; undated; 3 folders (Box 324, Folder 1-3)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to Kansas Indians, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Box 324, Folder 4)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to Minnesota Indians, 1955-1956; 1 folder (Box 324, Folder 5)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to Nevada Indians, 1954-1956; 1 folder (Box 324, Folder 6)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to New York Indians, 1947-1954; 1 folder (Box 324, Folder 7)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to Oregon Indians, 1952-1954; 1 folder (Box 324, Folder 8)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to Texas Indians, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Box 324, Folder 9)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to Utah Indians, 1953-1960; 1990; 3 folders (Box 325, Folder 1-3)
    - Termination of Federal Obligations to Washington Indians, 1953-1965; 1 folder (Box 325, Folder 4)